Mohammad Rahimi

Data Specialist

Profile

As a seasoned professional with 8 years of experience working with 5 distinguished companies, I have found my true passion in the field of data. With the ability to measure, control and analyse complex information, I believe that data is the power of the future.

My main trait is the ability to find the most efficient way to complete tasks, which requires a deep understanding of computer programming, critical thinking and creative problem solving.

Industrial Engineering has granted me the opportunity to study numerous subjects such as Probability Theory, Statistics, Mathematics Modeling, and Simulation.

I firmly believe that steady learning is extremely crucial to being successful. I am excited to apply my skills and knowledge to contribute to

Due to my strong adaptability and communication skills, I quickly match with any business environment. Additionally, during my time in supervision, I not only avoided acting as a traditional manager, but also focused on teamwork, including task assignment and delegation, as well as sharing my knowledge and professional experience with my colleagues.

Experience

Senior Data specialist at Mofid Securities, Tehran

(employees: >1500 people)

Jul 2020 - Jun 2024

Mofid Securities is Iran's largest full-service stock brokerage company and leading private investment advisory. In addition, the amount of Mofid total asset under management is about 1B\$ and the its proportion of daily trades is around one-third of market.

Currently, we exploite SQL Server, served with a Windows server, featured with Power Bi report server to support our data calculations, storage, visualization, and interpretation for the highest level of directors.

Some of our principal achievements:

- Scrap more than 98% of active funds in Iran to monitor market share
- Scrap monthly detailed portfolio entities of funds from Codal website
- Scrap historical parallel markets data such as Bahar coins, oil, gold, commodities, cryptocurrencies, Real estate, Inflation rate, etc.
- Conduct research and development in establishment of Index funds, Islamic leverage funds, and Capital Guarantee Funds, and sector funds.
- Setup portfolio managers key performance indexes (KPIs)
- Conduct an prototype for an internal trade core
- Monitor sales and marketing team performance based on strategies.
- Monitor the impact of any customer entrance gates and their portion in total revenue
- Prepare data required for marketing campaign and A-B test
- Collaborate with Data warehouse unit.

1 Information

Location: Iran +98 919 774 92 78

mohammadrahimy1991@gmail.com https://github.com/mrrahimy linkedin.com/in/mrahimy

Characteristic assessment results:

MBTI: ENTJ Holland: CEI



Problem solving Critical thinking Adaptability Teamwork

Python (Pandas, Numpy, Scikit learn, Matplotlib, Selenium, Web API) SQL Server (T-SQL) Power BI (DAX, M query) Excel (VBA/ Macros) Github LaTeX Linux (basics) CMD

Machine learning **Probability Statistics** Linear Algebra

Business Process Assessor at Techchi, Tehran

(employees: 10-15 people)

Jan 2020 - Jul 2020

- Visit and compose more than 30 reports of knowledge-based companies in terms of process maturity by localized Process Classification Framework (PCF) of American Productivity & Quality Center (APQC)
- Design and deploy a coding system for formal communications

Data & IT Consultant (freelancer), Tehran

(employees: >1000 people)

Apr 2016 – Sep 2019

Cooperate with 3 companies that were activated in knowledge-based ecosystem. Our most significant achievements are as follows:

- Propose Instructions, workflows and Procedures to facilitate the welfare of elites and Linchpins of knowledge-based companies
- Improve the user experience (UX) of the website and portal of knowledge-based companies by playing the role of product owner (PO)
- prepare knowledge-based products list, categorization, and criteria
- Evaluate the technology worth of microturbines, gas-fuel generators and Fuel cells

Education

MSc In Industrial Engineering at University of Tehran

Oct 2014- Oct 2017 (GPA: 18.00)

BSc in Industrial Engineering at Iran University of Science and Technology (IUST), Tehran

Oct 2010 - Oct 2014 (GPA: 17.34)

Interest & Vision

According to formal statistics my dream job is utilizing and incorporating Machine Vision, Machine Learning, deep learning, or any sort of data-driven science or technology to improve companies' process to achieve their goals precisely and rapidly.



English (IELTS 6.5)
Persian (native)